就如你们所听说的一样
As you may have already heard
我们收到一份邀请
we've received an invitation
准确来说
Or, more precisely,
那是份邀请你们小队
Your team has received an invitation
代表亚特兰蒂斯出席
to represent atlantis at a meeting
飞马座星系的
Of leaders from various human populations
人类领袖会议的请柬
throughout the pegasus galaxy.
这是什么  飞马座星系版的联合国吗
What's this, a pegasus version of the united nations?
没那个正式
Nothing quite so formal.
现在  只算是个不稳定的联盟
At the moment, it's more of a loose coalition.
这个所谓的联盟有什么先进技术吗
Is there any advanced technology in this "coalition"?
没有
No.
但是国际勘察顾问组织
But the i.o.a.
认为这是走向星际政府
Believes it could be an important
举足轻重的第一步
First step toward interplanetary government.
联邦政府  可以这样说
A... federation, if you will.
联邦有战舰
The federation had ships.
出席这个对我们有什么好处
Look, what do we hope to gain from this?
那些人能相互认识的唯一原因就是
The only reason these people even know about each other is
他们碰巧都继承了
Because they happened to inherit
古人的星门系统
the gate system from the ancients.
缺少高端的技术
Just because they lack advancement does
不代表他们不能联盟
Not mean they cannot benefit from cooperation.
所言甚是
She's right.
这个星系的人们
It's about time people in this galaxy
也是时候要自己当家做主了
Got together and stood up for themselves.
对付幽灵族吗
Against the wraith?
有何不可
Why not?
幽灵人正在自相残杀
The wraith are at war with each other,
现在正是时机
Which is why the people trying to
人类有所行动
Form this coalition feel the time is right.
他们也希望我们能参与其中
And they want us to be part of it.
联络委员稍后就到
The council liaison will be with you in a moment.
他们还特意为我们铺了红地毯
Wow, they're really rolling the red carpet out for us, huh?
我觉得他们倒是想把
I'm sure they're just trying to keep
这次会议保密
the details of this meeting secret.
同志们
Uh, guys...
形势不妙
Not good.
若楠
Ronon!
这是哪里
Where are we?
已经不在接待室
We're not in the same room.
我们被转移了
We've been moved.
发生什么事
What the hell happened?
问得好
That's a good question.
这是什么意思
What is the meaning of this?
待会你们便会知晓
It will all be explained shortly.
现在传召谢帕德中校
The council wishes to speak to lt. colonel sheppard.
我是来自洛提雅的科洛
I am kelore of latira.
她是希安娜  来自圣佛部落
This is shiana of the tribes of santhal,
最后是迪默  代表里瓦自由人民
And dimas of the free peoples of riva.
我们都是联盟的代表
We speak on behalf of the coalition.
如果你们不想别人知道这个地方
You know, if you wanted to keep this location secret,
大可蒙住我的双眼
You could have just blindfolded me.
我保证不会偷看
I wouldn't have peeked, I swear.
谢帕德中校
Lt.Colonel john sheppard,
你站在此地
You stand before this council
代表了整个亚特兰蒂斯小队的全体人员
as a representative of the atlantis expedition.
没问题
Okay.
正因如此  你有义务对以下的指控做出回答
And as such, it falls to you to answer the charges.
什么
Excuse me?
你会有足够的时间进行自我辩护
You will be given ample opportunity to present your defense,
陈词之后  我们再进行裁决
And when all evidence is heard, we will decide the outcome.
你他妈的说什么
What the hell are you talking about?
这是什么
What is this?
亚特兰蒂斯小队面临着
The atlantis expedition has been accused
伤害本星系人类的多项指控
Of crimes against the peoples of this galaxy.
现在进行审讯
This is your trial.
少校  发生什么事
Major, what happened?
长官  我们也在想办法搞清楚这事
We're still trying to figure that out, sir.
但可以确定的是  他们不在那村庄了
One thing's for sure, they're not in the village anymore.
他们不会事前不通知我们就擅自行动
They wouldn't have gone anywhere else without notifying us first.
是的  不会自发行动
Not voluntarily, no.
尽可能召集人手
Take as many men as you need.
进行全方位搜索
Search the entire area.
同时向村民打听他们的去向
And keep questioning the villagers.
肯定会有线索的
Somebody there knows something.
这本应是个友善的招待
This was supposed to be a meet-and-greet.
有鸡尾酒  精致点心小菜  舞蹈什么的
Just cocktails, hors d'oeuvres, maybe a little dancing?
借口推搪  在所难免
Subterfuge was necessary.
你们拥有的科学技术和军事火力
You possess technology and military power beyond the
在规模上和威力上都比本星系人类要大
Scope of most of the indigenous peoples of this galaxy.
因此  你们要被带到安全的地方审讯
Which is why you have been brought to a secure location.
只有议会成员和重要人员
Only the members of this council
才知道这里的星门拨号地址
and key personnel know the gate address.
别枉费心思  期盼有援兵到
So don't waste your time entertaining any hopes of rescue.
到底你们认为我们触犯了什么法律
What is it exactly that you think we did?
据统计  亚特兰蒂斯小队
According to our calculations, the atlantis expedition is responsible,
直接或间接
Directly or indirectly,
要对本星系2百万人口的死亡负责
For the deaths of over two million people in this galaxy.
开什么玩笑
You've got to be kidding me.
请陈述你们第一次和幽灵族碰头的情况
Tell us about your first encounter with the wraith.
好吧
Oh. okay.
我知道你要说什么
I see where this is going.
你到达的时候  幽灵族还在冬眠  不是吗
When you arrived here, the wraith were in hibernation, were they not?
并非个个如此
Not all of them.
什么意思
What do you mean?
我是说  他们袭击我们
I mean they attacked us.
那是什么
What is it?
幽灵人
The wraith!
击下那飞船
Take that thing down!
只是其中之一
That's one.
趴下
Get down!
泰勒
Teyla?
那只是一次侦查  并不是屠杀
That was a scouting party, not a culling.
我事先不知晓
Well, I didn't know that.
我只知道他们掳走了我们的人
All I know is they took our people.
然后你追击他们
And you went after them.
没错
That's right.
你该让他们自生自灭
You should have left them to their fate.
你们才会这么做
Oh, I'm sure that's what you would've done,
那可不是我们的惯常做法
but that's not how we operate.
后来怎么了
What happened?
我们潜进去
Well, we went in, we rescued
把人都救走  然后我们逃出来
as many people as we could, then we got out.
但是后来遇上了他们的女王
But not before encountering a queen.
是的
No.
这个你怎么得来的
How did this come to you?
不记得了
I don't remember.
引爆
Light it up!
你一定得死
That has to kill you.
长官  撤
Sir, let's go.
你不知道  你捅出个什么篓子
You don't know what you have done.
我们不过是沉睡中的族人们的看守者罢了
We are merely the caretakers for those that sleep.
我一死  他们就会醒觉
When I die, the others will awaken...
所有人
...all of them.
她说什么
What's she talking about?
外面还有多少幽灵人
How many are left?
如此说来  你承认了
So you admit it.
你唤醒了幽灵族
You woke the wraith.
他们醒觉也是迟早的事
Look, sooner or later, they were going to wake up on their own anyway.
但不是这一代
But not for generations.
中校
You see, colonel,
本星系的大部分人还没有
Most of the human populations of this galaxy have
从上次屠杀的阴影中走出来
Not yet fully recovered from the last round of cullings.
提前唤醒他们
As a result of this early awakening,
导致多个世界沦陷和灭亡
Several worlds have been driven to the point of
幸存者四散东西  他们的文明也没落消亡
Extinction-- their survivors scattered, their civilizations lost forever.
我们在外和幽灵人战斗  不分日夜
We're out there fighting the wraith, day after day,
我们的性命命悬一线
Putting our asses on the line.
但事实证明
But the fact remains,
如果你们不出现
Many who have been killed would be alive today
许多遇害者本可以逃过一劫
if you had never come here.
不是吗
Isn't that true?
够了  我没时间跟你玩
That's it, I'm not playing in this game anymore.
这只是众多指控中第一宗
This is just the first of many charges.
若你拒绝和我们合作
If you refuse to participate,
剩下的控罪会被判为罪名成立
It'll be taken as an admission of guilt on all counts,
然后我们唯有将你定罪
And we will have no choice but to proceed to sentencing.
那又如何
What are you going to do?
把亚特兰蒂斯的所有人都关进监狱吗
Put everybody in atlantis in jail?
很明显  这不可能
Obviously that's not possible.
但  我们能拒绝合作往来
However, we can refuse cooperation.
那就意味着停止商品交易  彼此之间不再牵扯任何关系
That means no more trade, no more relations of any kind.
亚特兰蒂斯将被孤立
Atlantis will be completely isolated.
不跟你们这帮人牵扯关系
No relations with the likes of you?
这不成问题
I think we can handle that.
联盟的体制与影响力在日益增强
The coalition grows in strength and influence every day.
很快
Soon enough,
你们当前的交易伙伴会别无选择
All of your current trading partners will have no choice but
加入并遵守议会的规定
To join and therefore to abide by the ruling of this council.
至于你的小队和你本人  我们要杀一儆百
As for you and your team, an example must be made.
这是公正之举
Justice demands it.
公正  你们管这个叫公正
Justice-- is that what you're calling this?
我们已经选好了一个荒无人烟的星球
A suitable, uninhabited planet has been chosen.
如果你们被判定有罪  就会被遣送过去
If you're found guilty, you'll be sent there, without any hope of return,
你的余生将没有可能再回来
For the rest of your naural life apparently,
他们所选的星球有足够维生的食物
The planet they picked for us has just enough food for us to survive,
技术上来说  并不是死刑
so, technically, it's not an execution.
太棒了
Great.
同时他们还有潜孔钻机
And they took the dhd,
所以不管谁一旦穿过星门  就再也回不来了
So whoever comes through the gate-- they're not coming back.
要是能有个地址
The  daedalus can find us.
泰达路斯就可以找到我们
If they had the address.
没有的话
Short of that,
他们就得搜遍银河系来才能找到我们
They'd need to search every solar system in the galaxy for a habitable
那差不多要花一百万年
planet, which would take, what, a million years?
对  我们不能慌
Right. let's not panic.
我已经在这地方待了一段时间了
I've been to the chamber a couple of times now.
我正在琢磨出路
I'm beginning to get a sense of the layout.
这里的建筑体系跟村子里的完全不一样
The architecture is definitely different from that of the village.
对  我们这是在另一个星球上
No, we're on another planet.
没有自然光线或者窗户
Judging by the fact there's no natural light or windows,
如此看来这是个井下储仓
I'm guessing an underground bunker.
卫兵呢
Guards?
嗯  六个或者更多
Yeah. half a dozen or so.
得想办法知道他们是否换班
We're going to have to see if they change in shifts.
无论如何也要让他们相信我们是无罪的
Any chance you could just convince them that we're not guilty?
事实如此  对吧
'cause we're not, right?
想想看
Oh, come on,
要不是我们的到来
There is no way the pegasus galaxy
飞马星系不可能有现在这么富裕
Would be better off if we'd never come here.
不
No.
相反的自从你来了  他们反而退步了
But since your arrival, there have been setbacks.
很多人丧生
Lives have been lost.
现在只不过是枯木逢春而已
But there is hope now where once there was none.
因为是我告诉他们去哪里做实验
As much as I'd like to tell these guys where to put their little trial,
在想出法子逃出去之前
We'll just have to play along for a while
我们应该暂时是盟友
until we figure out how to get out of here.
伍尔希先生  这是马瑞斯
Mr. woolsey, this is myrus.
他自称是新行星联盟的代表
He claims to be a representative for the new coalition of planets.
真的
Does he?
你是亚特兰蒂斯的指挥者吗
Are you the leader of atlantis?
没错
That's right.
我们得谈一谈
Then we need to speak.
议程上下一步要做什么
Well, what's next on the agenda?
这难道是我们最后一次踏足韦迪纳的玫瑰树林的事
Did we step on the rose bushes on our last trip to vedeena?
你应该听说过最近横扫几大世界的瘟疫了吧
Perhaps you've heard of a plague that's recently swept
这场疾病来得非常突然
Through several worlds, a sickness that arrives suddenly, runs
几天的时间就蔓延开来
Its course in a matter of days,
不管是男人  女人  还是孩子感染上了
And typically kills one out of every three men,
就有1/3的概率丧命
women, and children wherever it strikes.
有人坚信这根本就不是疾病
There are those who believe it is not a sickness at
而是蓄意的投毒  是个别人的行为
All but a deliberate poisoning, the work of one individual.
我知道你们在说谁
I know who you're talking about.
他叫迈克尔
His name is michael.
据说他既不是人类也不是幽灵人
It is said that he is neither human nor wraith,
而是混血
But some kind of half-breed.
对此  你有何解释吗
Can you explain to us how such a thing is possible?
我们中有人正在进行研究
One of our people was conducting research.
他们试图彻底解决
They were trying to come up with a way to
幽灵人带来的麻烦
Solve the wraith problem once and for all.
你们找到了把幽灵人转变成人类的法子吗
You found a way to convert wraith into humans?
别问我医学上的问题
Don't ask me the medical questions.
我可不是医生
I'm not a doctor.
那这个叫迈克尔的人是你们的测试对象之一吗
And this michael was one of your test subjects?
事实上  他是第一例
As a matter of fact, he was the first.
血压正常  脉搏平稳
Blood pressure's fine, pulse normal.
你现在复原得不错了
You're bouncing back quite nicely.
为什么说是复原
Bouncing back from what?
你好  迈克尔
Hello, michael.
还记得我吗
Do you remember me?
不
No.
我是伊丽莎白·韦尔博士
I'm dr. elizabeth weir.
这是约翰·谢帕德中校
This is  colonel john sheppard.
你是我的部下
You served under my command.
你的全名是迈克尔·肯摩尔中尉
Your name is lieutenant michael kenmore.
你现在是在亚特兰蒂斯的一所私人诊疗室
You're in a private room off the infirmary here in atlantis.
想起什么来了吗
Is that familiar to you?
亚特兰蒂斯
Atlantis...
对  是吧
Yeah. I think.
我们尝试着让他相信  他是我们中的一员
We tried to convince him he was one of us.
但他清楚有地方不对劲  然后他找出了证据
But he knew something was wrong, and then he found proof.
5毫克
Five milligrams!
放开我
Release me!
你将为此丧命
You will die for this!
其他人会来救我的
Others will come for me!
-他们会...  -省省吧
They will-- blah blah blah .
他们得先能找到我们再说
They've got to find us first.
得给你起个名字
You're going to need a name.
迈克尔怎么样
How does "mike" sound?
在那以后  他出逃了
After that, he escaped.
他在人类与幽灵人之中踌躇徘徊了很久
He went back and forth between wraith and human a couple
最终在选择了一个折中的地方定居下来
More times until he finally settled somewhere in between.
这么说来你再次承认了你的罪行
So once again you admit your guilt.
你们把这东西...放到银河系
You unleashed this...thing on the galaxy.
我们并不是主动放走他  而且也没有对其放任不管
We didn't just let him out the front door and forget about him.
自从他逃走那刻起我们就一直在找
We've been chasing him ever since.
几个月前   我们终于找到了他
A couple of months ago, we managed to catch up with him.
准备引爆
Fire in the hole.
发生什么事
What happened?
超时空引擎发生爆炸
The hyperdrive just exploded.
不  这不可能
No, that's impossible.
飞船主电力系统不足
Main power is out across much of the ship.
意外超负荷
An accidental overload?
那也不可能
It doesn't appear that way.
那是什么回事
How did they do that?
我去看看
I will look into it.
泰达路斯  请接入
Daedalus,  please come in.
谢帕德中校  你们的飞船怎么了
Colonel sheppard, what the hell happened to your jumper?
我在停车场上来回寻觅
Hell, I got all turned around in the parking garage.
匆忙之下  只好借用这架幽灵战斗机
I was in a rush, so I borrowed this dart.
我即将通过牵引进入存储仓
I've got the team beamed in to a storage device.
那巡洋舰随便你怎么处理吧
Feel free to do whatever you want to that cruiser.
马克斯少校  让那艘飞船消失吧
Major marks, please make that ship go away.
遵命  长官
Yes, sir.
你确定他已经死了吗
Are you sure he was killed?
整艘船都毁了  无人生还
The ship was vaporized. there was no body to recover.
也就是说你无法在议会跟古人的眼下
Well, then, you cannot testify before this council,
证明这点了
And under the eyes of the ancestors,
你不能确认他的死讯
That you know for certain that he is dead.
不
No.
这真是太无礼了
This is outrageous.
你这是告诉我  新政府成立的首要任务是
You're telling me that one of the first official acts
袭击并诱拐我们这些人吗
Of your new government was to assault and kidnap my people?
谈不上袭击
They weren't assaulted.
只是逮捕而已
They were arrested.
你这是跟我开玩笑吧
You've got to be kidding me.
相信我  不是所有人都同意这项决定
Believe me, not all of us agreed with this decision,
但是  事出有因
But it wasn't taken entirely without reason.
我们一直在努力帮助你们
We've been trying to help you people.
你们片面的决定无凭无据极不负责
What you've been doing is making unilateral decisions that affect
使数以百万计的人丧命
The lives of millions, without consultation and without accountability.
这样的情况我们不能再容忍了
This is no longer acceptable.
我不想和你在这里争论
I'm not going to get drawn into a debate here.
我想问你一句话  我们的人被关在哪儿
I only need to know one thing-- where are my people being held?
这肯定不能告诉你
Of course I can't tell you that.
正当的审问是不用遮遮掩掩的
Fair trials don't take place in secret locations.
就算如此...
Nevertheless
看来马如斯先生需要好好认清一下自己的处境
Mr.Myrus needs a little time to reconsider his position here.
把他押进牢房
Escort him to a cell.
立即执行
My pleasure.
你犯了个大错
You're making a mistake.
是吗
Am i?
当我被选作信使的时候
When I was chosen to deliver this message,
我就知道自己有可能回不去了
I knew there was a chance I wouldn't be coming back.
但如果你扣押我
But if you detain me,
就证实了许多人的怀疑
You will only be confirming what many already suspect-- that you're a
你们是银河系里无法无天的流氓群体
Rogue element in this galaxy, operating without restraint or due process.
把他关起来
Lock him up.
好吧
All right.
我不是说我们一点错都没犯过
I'm not saying we haven't made some mistakes,
可那是因为只有我们在战斗
But that's 'cause we're the only ones out there fighting.
没有其他人敢站出来对抗幽灵族了
Nobody else is out there taking on the wraith.
但那不也是你们的错吗
But isn't that your own fault as well?
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
杰纳人本来是准备去对付幽灵族的
The genii had a plan to combat the wraith,
而后来他们却没有  是因为你们背叛了他们
But they were thwarted when you betrayed them.
他们是这样说的吗
Oh, is that what they told you?
恐怕我有不同意见
Because that's not what I remember.
我父亲呢
Where's my father?
他没能活下来
He did not survive.
怎么会
How?
发生什么了
What happened?
我们会查明的
I think we should find out.
瞄准目标
Take aim!
科文  我们好像刚同意和平相处吧
Cowen, I thought we were just learning how to get along.
她杀了泰卢斯
She killed tyrus.
没有
No.
眼睁睁看着他咽气和杀死他没什么区别
By leaving him to die, you may just as well have killed him yourself.
我们要把你们的情报资料和飞船
We will keep this intelligence information and your ship,
加上所有的炸药全都扣下
And whatever quantities of c4 you have in your possession.
你们早就计划好了是么  利用我们
That is all you ever intended-- to use us.
放下武器
Your weapons.
不可能  开什么玩笑
No. I don't think so.
你父亲会死的瞑目吗
This is what your father died for?
对称自己为"朋友"的人撒谎
In the name of people who would lie and
并进行洗劫
Steal from those they would call friends?
我也撒谎了
Well, I lied too.
飞船2号  3号  行动
Jumpers two and three, execute.
你真当我们只有一辆飞船啊
Did you really think we had one ship?
这么说来你们是互相背叛了
So you betrayed each other.
我们只不过是有备而来  他们先动的手
We came prepared. they made the first move.
杰纳人的计划根本不可能成功
Look, the genii plan was never going to work anyways.
没有我们帮助  他们连炸弹都造不出
They had bombs they couldn't finish without our help,
而且他们也不懂得如何传送
They had no methods of delivery.
若想战胜幽灵  靠我们才有希望
If you want a military victory against the wraith, we're your only chance.
你和外星系的人联系过了吗
You've been in touch with our off-world contacts?
是的  长官
Yes, sir.
结果呢
And?
谁都不清楚状况
Nobody knows anything.
至少他们是这么说的
At least, that's what they're saying.
你相信了?
You don't believe them?
老实说  现在我都不知道该相信谁了
Well, frankly, right now, I don't know what to believe, sir.
他们应该是我们的盟友
These people are supposed to be our friends,
但如果我们就这样走进一个村庄
But if we can't just walk into an ordinary village
肯定会怕中埋伏的  怎么会这样
Without worrying about an ambush, what's the point?
还没到这地步
We're not there yet.
我不相信整个银河系都视我们为敌
I refuse to believe that the whole galaxy has turned against us.
最好如此  因为现在我们可以说是一无所有
Well, it might as well, because right now we have nothing.
也许不是
Maybe not...
跟我来
Come with me.
开门
Open it.
马卢斯先生  我有一个提议
Mr. myrus, I have a proposal for you.
你是说你们在军事上战胜过幽灵?
So you claim to have had military success against the wraith?
我们给他们造成了一定的破坏
We've done our share of damage.
甚至还能把一些蜂巢飞船转移
Even managed to take a few hive ships out here and there.
是吗
Really?
你们是如何完成这些伟大成就的
And how did you manage to accomplish this remarkable feat?
强调一点  这绝非易事
Well, I can tell you one thing-- it's never easy,
但稍使计谋  就能让他们自相残杀
But one good trick is to get them to shoot at each other.
看到了吗
Look. see that?
幽灵开始攻击蜂巢战斗机了
It's a dart firing at one of the hive ships.
为什么
Why?
谢帕德
Sheppard.
谢帕德居然能让他们自己人打自己人
Sheppard's actually getting them to fire at each other.
两架蜂巢飞船对攻的时候
If two hive ships are going at it and you happen to
无论你在哪一架上面  形势都不容乐观
Be onboard one of them, that can be a bit of a problem.
所以一定要随机应变
That's when you have to improvise.
泰勒  罗恩  进来
Teyla, lorne, come in.
中校  你在哪儿
Colonel, where are you?
正往你那儿赶
We're on our way.
赶快  那些蜂巢舰发现我们了
You must hurry. the other hive has found us.
你们能顶住吗
Can you hold 'em off?
顶不了多久
Not for long.
进入飞船停泊岗
Approaching dart bay.
收到
Acknowledged.
他们进来了
They're inside.
中校  我们请求立刻进入超空间
Colonel, request permission to jump to hyperspace immediately.
不行  我有一个主意
Negative. I have another idea.
泰勒  改变线路
Teyla, I want you to set a new course.
长官
Commander.
什么事
What is it?
我们刚从蜂巢舰那里收到一个紧急通报
We just received an urgent communication from the hive.
敌人正朝我们驶来
The enemy-- they're headed straight for us.
我还说过我们常利用古人技术
Did I also mention that we have a fair amount of ancient
真的非常方便
Technology at our disposal, because that can be pretty handy too.
有一架蜂巢舰正在朝你开火
There's a hive bearing down on your position.
是的  长官  我看见了
Yes, sir, I see that.
什么都别做
Stand by.
医生  我们会死在这儿的
Doc, they're killing us here.
我知道  我知道
I have it, I have it.
火链袭击
Firing drones.
让我想想  还漏了什么
Let's see, what else did I leave out?
都这么多年了  想全记住还真不容易
There's been so many over the years, you know, it's hard to keep track.
够了
Enough.
你把自己说得天花乱坠  中校
You spin a colorful tale, colonel.
这牛吹的还真大
That much is obvious.
全凭你一面之辞  没有证据不行
Yet for all these fantastic claims, we have no evidence but your word.
这次审问就是证据
This trial is evidence.
现在你们坐在这里审讯我
None of this would be happening-- your
要不是我们把幽灵族打退的话
Precious little coalition wouldn't even exist if we
你们这个小联盟早就灭亡了
Hadn't have pushed the wraith so far back that you
现在算是你们万年一遇的机会
Got an opportunity you haven't had in 10,000 years.
你们在这件事上需要负的责任已经很清楚了
Your responsibility in this has already been determined.
这个星系里的人口恢复之前
You woke the wraith early,
你们就唤醒了幽灵族
Before the population of this galaxy had sufficient time to recover,
导致了那些幽灵族在食物区开战
Which eventually led to the wraith going to war with each other over feeding grounds.
是这场战争给了我们机会
That war is what has given us this opportunity,
而不是你们所谓的胜利
Not some imagined victory on your part.
暂时休庭
We will take a recess.
请将犯人带回牢房
Please take the prisoner back to his cell.
伍尔希  你在这儿干嘛
Woolsey, what the hell are you doing here?
我和他们达成了一个协议
I've made an arrangement with your captors.
我来替你接受审问
I'm taking over your defense.
你不会带了一个子空间的定位器吧
I don't suppose you managed to bring along a subspace locator beacon, did you?
那是幽灵族的技术
That's wraith technology.
不是我们随手就能拿到的
It's not like we have one just lying around.
我甚至还去问过泰德  看看能否借一个
I even tried to contact todd to see if we could borrow one,
他都没给我回音
But he never responded.
用我们在星球上埋伏的拨号装置怎么样
What about the dhd on the planet we were ambushed?
可以查到最近拨出的地址
You could pull the most recent addresses that were dialed from there.
查过了
Already done.
缓冲区里有至少50个地址
There were over 50 addresses in the buffer.
我几乎把整个城翻个底朝天
I almost cleaned out the entire city sending people
派人寻访了每一处  毫无结果
To investigate all of them, but they turned up nothing.
他们带我们穿越了不止一道门
They took us through more than one gate.
貌似是的
So it would seem.
这谁都想得到
This was obviously very well thought out.
他们计划得很好
They had a very clever plan,
但我们更聪明  更有准备
But we're smarter and better armed.
周围肯定还有其他的路
There's got to be a way around this.
他们利用了我们最大的弱点
They took advantage of one significant weakness--
我们相信他们
We trusted them.
听着  我来这是因为
Look, I came here because
我想到了带大家出去的办法
I have a plan to get you out of here.
什么办法
Well, what is it?
赢得审判
Win the trial.
听着
Look,
我们一直在努力赢取
We were just playing along to buy us
足够时间离开这儿
Enough time to figure out a way out of here.
结果如何呢
And how's that coming along?
我们  我们还在努力
Well, we're-- we're working on it.
我是哈佛的法学评论员
I was harvard law review.
陆军工程兵团的首席顾问
I was chief counsel of the us army corps of engineers.
在此之前  我作为辩护律师
Prior to that, I was an appellate advocate
为哈茨霍恩和斯洛特上诉
For hartshorne & slaughter,
此案成为全纽约闻名的
One of the most prestigious litigation
经典案例之一
Boutiques in all new york city.
相信我  我能用一堆草纸告倒三个长老级人物
Believe me, I can handle three tribal elders with a stack of papyrus.
前些天
Some time ago,
人类世界遭到了
A number of human worlds
来自宇宙的攻击
Were attacked and destroyed from space,
不是幽灵干的  而是另有其人
Not by the wraith, but by someone else.
我们对这场神秘之战知之甚少
Little is known of this mysterious race
除了攻击者拥有超高的先进技术
Except that they possess incredibly advanced technology,
和他们来自亚特兰蒂斯联盟的传言
End are rumored to be allies of atlantis.
我想我知道你指的是谁  相信我
I think I know who you're referring to, and believe me,
我们不跟他们合作
They are not our allies.
他们叫复制人
They're called replicators.
是被古人创造出来的
They were created by the ancients.
你想知道我们的真实身份
If you wish to know the truth of who we are,
我带你去看
I will show you.
你们所谓的古人
The ancients, as you call them,
在研究如何打败幽灵的过程中
Were desperate in their search
举步维艰
for a better way to fight the wraith.
虽然人数上占很大优势
Though greatly outnumbered,
他们还是依靠科技的
They relied on their technological
优势占据了有利地位
Superiority to give them a needed advantage.
他们并没有一味制造
Instead of building
更大更强的武器
bigger, more powerful weapons,
而是选择制造小型武器
They chose to build smaller ones.
那奈斯（小型杀伤性武器）
Nanites.
这些小型杀伤性武器里
In these tiny killing machines,
古人们赋予的攻击能力
The ancients imbued an aggression
远远超过了敌人的
that surpassed even that of their enemy.
这项技术实现了有机同化
The technology allowed for organic assimilation
能让人自我复制  提高了效率
And self-replication to increase their effectiveness.
然而真的复制成功了
And replicate they did.
人数成倍增长
They grew in numbers,
速度让古人们都感吃惊
Evolving at a rate that took the ancients by surprise.
分子机器联合运作
The molecular machines began interlocking,
合力提供更多复杂生物
Assembling themselves to form even more complex organisms,
最终进化到他们想到的
Eventually evolving into the most
最高效形式
effective and efficient form they knew of.
于是我们诞生了
This is how we were born.
然而古人们发现我们成不了
When the ancients concluded that we would never become
他们设想的武器  他们决定中止
The weapon they desired to create, they decided to end it.
想把我们杀光  一个不留
So they chose to destroy us, to leave no trace of us behind.
但还是有些幸存者
Some of them managed to survive.
没错
That's right.
正如其名
And as the name suggests,
他们不断复制直至重建成一股强大力量
They replicated and rebuilt themselves into a powerful force.
天哪
Oh... my...
开玩笑吧
No kidding.
那他们为何攻击人类
But why would they attack human worlds?
这是他们对抗幽灵计划的一部分
It was a strategy they developed in their campaign
断绝他们的食物来源
Against the wraith-- eliminate the enemy's food supply.
还有一件事我不明白  伍尔希先生
There's one thing I don't understand, mr. Woolsey.
如果你说的是真的  他们最初是用来对抗幽灵的
If, as you suggest, they were originally designed to fight the wraith,
为什么要等到现在
Why did they wait until now?
我拿到点模块了  我们走
I got the zpm. we're leaving.
等一下  不能走
Wait a minute. we can't go.
你说什么
What are you talking about?
你说你能在线操控的
You said you could get the hyperdrive back online.
我说了  但不是现在
I mean, we can, but not yet.
听着  伊丽莎白联接的时候
Look, while elizabeth's been connected,
我们搜索了复制人的编码
I've been going over the replicators' base code,
我找到了这个
and I found this.
那是什么
What is that?
圣杯
The holy grail.
他们存在的唯一目的
It's their whole reason for being.
一个指引他们攻击幽灵的命令代码
It's a command code that directs them to attack the wraith.
对  但他们没有攻击幽灵
Yeah, but they don't attack the wraith.
他们已经在复制系统里住了N年
They've been sitting on their nanite asses for 10,000 years.
那是因为指令失效了
That's because it's been deactivated.
你是说是你们
Are you telling us that you are the ones
激活了攻击编码
that activated the attack code?
我们也不知道他们会攻击人类世界
We didn't know they were going to target human worlds.
但就是因为你们莽撞行事
No, because you acted rashly,
不计后果
without considering the consequences.
我们好不容易才有机会
We had an opportunity,
机不可失  时不再来
one that wasn't going to present itself again.
请相信我  我们并非草率决定
Believe me, councilors, this decision was not taken lightly.
其实我们已经损失了一名最优秀的成员
In fact, it cost us one of our best people.
伊丽莎白
Elizabeth...
快上飞船
Get to the jumper.
你跟我们一起上船
You're coming with us.
我马上就要冻不住他们了
I can't keep them frozen much longer.
我们不会把你丢下
We're not leaving you behind.
如果你现在不走
If you don't leave right now,
谁都走不了了  快走
none of us will get out of here, so go!
这是命令
That's an order!
快
Come on!
伊丽莎白
Elizabeth!
走!
Go!
你们死了一个人
One of your people died,
你认为这就是巨大的牺牲?
and you consider this a grave sacrifice?
事实上  是的
As a matter of fact, I do.
那考虑一下我们的感受
Then imagine how we feel-- those of us
我们眼睁睁看着无数人死掉
Who have witnessed the deaths of thousands.
复制人这么做不能怪罪到我们头上
We cannot be held responsible for the actions of the replicators.
谢帕德中校从幽灵的角度提出了同样的问题
Colonel sheppard made the same argument in respect to the wraith,
这种情况下我倒倾向于他的说法
And in that case I might be inclined to agree with him.
你也承认复制人是机器
By your own admission, these replicators are machines.
那是否我杀了一个人
So if I were to set a detonator,
可以说不是我杀的  是刀杀的
Can I then later deny responsibility for the actions of the bomb?
按你的逻辑  那古人也有责任了
By that logic, you might just as well blame the ancients.
古人创造了复制者
They created them.
你口中所谓的古人
The ancients, as you call them,
不在现场  无法做证
are not here to answer for their actions.
但你可以
You are.
到目前为止有六个人类世界
We know for certain of six human worlds
都被复制人给摧毁了
That were destroyed by the replicators.
但同时也有十几个
But we also know of at least a dozen
蜂巢战舰被毁
hive ships that were destroyed,
蜂巢战舰基本上一年之内都不会在战场出现了
Hive ships that would almost certainly have culled within a year.
总的来说  两相抵消
One could make the argument that, on balance,
获救的人比牺牲的人多
More lives were saved than were lost.
两相抵消?
On balance?
我们对你而言就这点意义?
Is that what we are to you?
一个一个死  最后都得死
Figures on a ledger?
游戏的规则是一命换一命
Pieces that can be moved about in a game of strategy,
有人获救就得有人牺牲吗
Some to be saved while others are sacrificed?
对不起
I'm sorry,
我也不想以牺牲为代价
I certainly didn't mean to diminish--
活生生的人被杀  伍尔希先生
real people are being killed, mr.Woolsey
村镇在倾颓  我的家园  我的同胞
real villages destroyed-- my village, my people.
我的丈夫和孩子在我面前死去
My husband and children-- murdered before my eyes.
你的星球也被复制人毁了
You're from one of the planets destroyed by the replicators.
我捡回一条命
I barely escaped with my life,
但眼见着我珍视的一切
But not before I saw everything I hold dear
随着一束光照便消失得无影无踪了
Get wiped out by a beam of light from the sky.
直到有人为此付出代价  我才会停止战斗
And I will not rest until someone is made to pay for it.
看来她是不可能投我们的票了
Well, I guess we can rule out getting her vote.
委员里不应该有这么偏激的人
It's clearly inappropriate for someone that biased to be on the council.
他们就会全体反对我们
So they stacked the deck against us.
我也不确定
I'm not sure.
迪默看起来还是挺讲道理的
Dimas seems to be a reasonable man.
我想劝劝他还是有可能站我们这边的
I think he might even be persuaded to vote our way.
不知道科洛怎么想的
Kelore is a little harder to read.
是啊  他貌似对我充满敌意
Yeah, he seemed pretty hostile to me.
你说他来自洛提雅
Didn't you say he was from latira?
是啊  没错
Yeah, that's right.
我们的一项智能报告表明
One of our last intelligence reports suggests a
洛提雅人和杰纳人之间的关系日渐紧密
Growing relationship between latira and the genii.
是啊
Yeah,
他以前是跟我说过
He did try to convince me that they should be
他们应该带头对抗幽灵
The ones leading the fight against the wraith.
你觉得杰纳人是幕后黑手?
You think the genii are behind this?
说得通
It makes sense.
除了亚特兰蒂斯
Apart from atlantis,
他们显然是联盟里最强的军事力量
They're clearly the biggest military power in the coalition.
如果走对了棋
If they played their cards right,
他们最终会掌控局势
They could wind up running the whole thing.
除非我们不插手
But only with us out of the picture.
原来我们一直是对的  事情解决了
So we were right all along. this whole thing's fixed.
我觉得应该实行B计划  等守卫进来  我就上
I say we go to plan b-- wait for the guards come in, I beat 'em up,
抢走枪  一路杀出去
Take their guns, we shoot our way out of here.
我们还知道路么
Do we even know the way out?
我们至少在地下二层
We know we're at least two levels underground and
不过十几个守卫
There's no more than a dozen or so guards at any one time.
那地面上呢
What about on the surface?
上面有多少守卫
How many guards are up there?
门在哪儿  有多远
And which way is the gate? and how far?
路上我们慢慢想
There's a few things we'll have to figure out along the way.
太冒险了
It's too risky.
出去之前我们可能就没命了
We could wind up being shot before we even got out of the building.
还有别的选择么
What other choice do we have?
我们肯定赢不了的
We know we can't win this thing.
不全是
Not fairly, no.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
我是说既然知道游戏规则  我就能玩了
I'm saying now that I know what the game is, I can play it.
科洛  感谢你能会见我
Kelore, thank you for agreeing to meet me.
在外面守着
Wait outside.
我给了他一块父亲留给我的怀表
It cost me rather a fine pocketwatch that used
他才带我来的
To belong to my father to get him to bring me here.
你不用这么费心的
You shouldn't have bothered.
我什么都做不了
There's nothing I can do for you.
那就当我今晚特大方吧
Well, maybe I'm just feeling generous tonight.
有什么直说吧
Speak plainly.
你站错边了
You're backing the wrong horse.
我们知道你与杰纳人有联系
We know you're connected with the genii.
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
我还知道他们想成为
We also know they're looking to become
联盟背后的军事力量
The military muscle behind the coalition.
得做个选择了
We think we'd make a better choice.
你?  还是亚特兰蒂斯?
You? atlantis?
是的
That's right.
我还不知道你有如此雄心壮志
Well, I didn't realize you had those kinds of ambitions.
迄今为止我们都很满意
We've been content to keep to ourselves up until now,
但对于是淘汰出局还是积极参与
But if it's a choice between getting pushed out of the game and
结果肯定不言而喻  对吧
Taking a more active part, well, that's no choice at all, is it?
当然  也不能太张扬  得装装门面
Of course, for appearance's sake, we can't be too aggressive,
所以我们需要有人在内部接应
So we'll need someone on the inside to help push our agenda...
此人日后必当重谢
Someone to whom we'll be very, very grateful.
我如何确保你没有向别人提出请求
And how do I know you haven't made this offer to the others?
你我深知迪默只相信真理
I think we both know dimas will only be swayed by reason,
希安娜无论如何都会投反对票
And shiana's going to vote against us, no matter what.
就剩你了
That leaves you.
伍尔希先生  准备好面对最终判决了么
Mr. woolsey, are you ready to face the final charge?
是的
I am.
亚特兰蒂斯人民被起诉与幽灵勾结
The people of atlantis stand accused of conspiring with the wraith.
勾结
Conspiring?
有人举报亚特兰蒂斯与幽灵协商
We have reports that atlantis has negotiated with
并与其进行军事演习
The wraith and performed military operations with them.
据称你与其中一名幽灵建立了联盟
It is said you have formed an alliance with one wraith in particular.
泰德
Todd.
我们就这么叫他
That's what we call him.
他与谢帕德中校一同被杰纳人关进监狱
This wraith was imprisoned with colonel sheppard by the genii.
幽灵可以吃了他  尽管如此
The wraith was allowed to feed on him but, despite this,
谢帕德中校发现
Colonel sheppard realized that their
只有合作才有逃生的希望
Best chance of escape was to work together.
哪条路
Which way?
这条路
This way.
你们一直和这个幽灵有来往?
And you continue to have dealings with this wraith?
偶尔有接触
We have... occasional contact.
你相信他
You trust him?
当然不
Of course not.
但他有时很有用
But he has proven to be useful at times.
他帮助我们拖住复制人的飞船  争取时间
He helped us hold off the replicator fleet long enough for dr.Mckay
以便麦凯博士想出计划摧毁他们
To enact a plan to destroy them.
内部吸收
Interior suction.
将非关键系统的能量用于船体再生
Transferring power from non-critical systems to hull regeneration.
我们的防护快承受不住了  长官
Our shields can't take much more of this, sir.
可喜可贺  已经不用了
Hopefully, they won't have to.
准备将光子武器的能量转入
And get ready to transfer power from the beam weapons to the--
什么东西
What the hell?
狗娘养的
Son of a bitch.
他真这么干了
He actually did it.
得赶快离开这儿
We need to get out of here.
好的  走吧  快
Right. let's go. come on!
虽然很想  但我们不应该在这儿看着它垮掉
As much as I'd love to, we shouldn't stick around and watch this go down.
应该通知船队立刻去汇合点
We should tell the fleet to jump to the rendezvous point immediately.
星球不稳定了
The planet's become unstable.
事实上没有他的帮助我们不可能打败复制人
The fact is we would never have defeated the replicators without his help.
可以说他们将会一直攻击人类
I think it's safe to say they would have continued their policy of
那样的话  到如今银河系里的人就死光了
Attacking human worlds and, by now, everyone in this galaxy would be dead.
很好
Very well.
作为最后判决  我们将休庭讨论
As that was the final charge, we will recess to deliberate.
如果可以的话  我想做最后的陈述
I'd like to make one final statement, if I may.
说吧
Very well.
幽灵正在起内讧  但不会长久
The wraith are in disarray, but that won't last forever.
有一方迟早会胜利
Sooner or later, one faction will win out over the others.
一旦发生
And when that happens,
他们会将冷酷仇视的目光射向联盟
They will turn their attention to this coalition with a
这是你们闻所未闻的
Ruthless vengeance, the likes of which you've never seen.
如果真有这么一天  你们也不想要我们的援助
If you don't want us there when that day comes, fighting by your side,
请务必投我们有罪
Then, by all means, vote us guilty.
我不需要讨论了
I need no deliberation.
我提议当场表决
I say we get this over with now.
可以
Very well.
我赞成所有指控
I vote guilty, on all charges.
我不赞成所有指控
I vote not guilty on all charges.
就看你了  科洛
It falls to you, kelore.
你是关键的一票
Yours is the deciding vote.
怎么说
Well? what's the word?
无罪
Not guilty.
谢天谢地
Oh, thank god.
我们可以走了
We're free to go.
我从没怀疑过你的能力
I never doubted you for a second.
西装不错
Whoo, nice suit.
一上法庭我就想念我的制服了
Being back in the courtroom made me miss my old uniform.
不会吧
You're kidding.
不想工作  只想制服
Not the job, just the uniform.
味道不错
Oh, that's nice.
这样更好
Well, it seemed appropriate.
跟我说说你是怎么搞定的
So, you going to tell me how you managed to pull this one off?
要我说这是综合效应  我的法律技巧
Well, I'd say it was a combination of things-- my legal skills,
我的口才  我的论点  充满逻辑无懈可击
My eloquence, the indisputable logic of my arguments,
还有给科洛的贿赂
And the bribe I offered kelore.
是啊
Mm. yeah.
关键是
On top of that,
我得保证亚特兰蒂斯在银河系飞马座
I had to commit atlantis to a much larger
每天都参与到政治中来
Day-to-day participation in the politics of the pegasus galaxy.
得想个法子写进报告里...
A way to explain that in my report...
是啊
Yeah...
有影响力才是最重要的  对吧
What's the point of being out here if we don't try to make a difference, right?
希望勘察顾问组织也这么想
Let's hope the i.o.a. agrees with you.
这个不用急
Let's worry about that later.
现在  恭喜贺喜
For now, congratulations.
多谢
Thanks.